<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title></title>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://kafkaa.xyz/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://kafkaa.xyz/"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://kafkaa.xyz/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Going Forward</title>
        <published>2024-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Manoprasanth MATHAVAN
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://kafkaa.xyz/blog/going-forward/"/>
        <id>https://kafkaa.xyz/blog/going-forward/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://kafkaa.xyz/blog/going-forward/">&lt;p&gt;For a past a few years, there exists a chaos in my mind to share my thoughts online. I have never been comfortable with voicing out my thoughts online. That’s also one of the reasons why I stopped using Social Media. Kafkaa belongs to me, I built it from scrach yet I never found solace in it as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;gf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Picture of Hayao Miyazaki&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever an idea strikes me regarding a blog or something, I kinda feel insecure and devle into the rabbit hole of overthinking. I always end up questioning myself with the following. Am I knowledgeable enough as the people I look up to in the same space to create something? Am I being true to myself or just doing it for the content? Am I being passionate enough? and the list goes on and on. The mere fact that I didn’t produce anything substantial with my skills is the key reason for all these thoughts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, it changes now. From here on, Kafkaa will emerge as a space I always envisioned. I don’t care if the blogs I write are mediocre and the projects I make seem to be middling. Its the process, and has always been the process which I loved being in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these days, I will be as good as the people I look upto. Even if I don’t quite make it, I won’t feel any remose. I will cherish the process.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not some random motivation rants. I have been working on myself for quite a while now. And I felt that this is the right moment to do this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
From here on, Kafkaa will emerge as a space I always envisioned.
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes fate is like a small sandstorm that keeps changing directions. You change direction but the sandstorm chases you. You turn again, but the storm adjusts. Over and over you play this out, like some ominous dance with death just before dawn. Why? Because this storm isn’t something that blew in from far away, something that has nothing to do with you. This storm is you. Something inside of you. So all you can do is give in to it, step right inside the storm, closing your eyes and plugging up your ears so the sand doesn’t get in, and walk through it, step by step. There’s no sun there, no moon, no direction, no sense of time. Just fine white sand swirling up into the sky like pulverized bones. That’s the kind of sandstorm you need to imagine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you really will have to make it through that violent, metaphysical, symbolic storm. No matter how metaphysical or symbolic it might be, make no mistake about it: it will cut through flesh like a thousand razor blades. People will bleed there, and you will bleed too. Hot, red blood. You’ll catch that blood in your hands, your own blood and the blood of others. And once the storm is over you won’t remember how you made it through, how you managed to survive. You won’t even be sure, in fact, whether the storm is really over.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
But one thing is certain. When you come out of the storm you won&#x27;t be the same person who walked in. That&#x27;s what this storm&#x27;s all about.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Haruki Murakami&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>A month without media consumption</title>
        <published>2024-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Manoprasanth MATHAVAN
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://kafkaa.xyz/blog/no-media-consumption/"/>
        <id>https://kafkaa.xyz/blog/no-media-consumption/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://kafkaa.xyz/blog/no-media-consumption/">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I have had a notion to track my life. So, I started to track a few things since January ’24. Up until now my idea was just to track my actions and understand my habits better rather than pushing myself to maintain a streak on the actions. To give you an idea here is the representation of days on which I was reading a book.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;reading.png&quot;  alt=&quot;Days spent reading&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was probing for something on the Internet, I serendipitously ended up in this &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manuelmoreale.com&#x2F;without&quot;&gt;blog by Manu&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. To give you a brief, he gives up something for a month like caffine, videogames and then evaluate whether it was something he enjoyed giving up, and try to comprehend if it’s worth leaving it out of his life. It seemed fun and interesting so I decicded to give it a shot.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, for the month of June I decided to give up media cosumption, to narrow it down I decided to stop watching any form of moving images ranging from Youtube videos, Films, TV Series, Documentaries, or any form of Social Media.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though I didn’t fail miserably in this challenge. I managed to refrain from consuming media for the first ten days which is a small win to cherish for and after which I fell into the old patterns.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key observation during the initial phase was that my screen time drastically dropped from hours to minutes which I didn’t account for while planning. Also, I spent a lot of time reading. Another important thing was utter boredom, I was expecting to be hit by one eventually. Although going through it was kind of horrendous, it rekindled the good old days when I wasn’t connected to the Internet. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Yaanai Doctor - A journey into the world of Elephant Healing</title>
        <published>2023-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Manoprasanth MATHAVAN
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://kafkaa.xyz/blog/yaanai-doctor/"/>
        <id>https://kafkaa.xyz/blog/yaanai-doctor/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://kafkaa.xyz/blog/yaanai-doctor/">&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;yd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Book of Yannai Doctor&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, during a visit to Panuval bookstore in Chennai, I came across a book by Jeyamohan, an author whose works I hadn’t explored before. While I had never felt a particular fascination for Jeyamohan’s writings, I decided to take a leap of faith and chose to delve into his world. I picked up two of his works, “Iravu” (Nights) and “Yaanai Doctor” (The Elephant Doctor).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&#x27;டாக்டர் நம்ம பசங்க மாதிரி சபிக்கப்பட்ட தலைமொறை இந்தியாவிலே இருந்ததில்லை. அவங்க முன்னாடி இன்னிக்கு நிக்கிறதெல்லாமே வெறும் கட்டவுட்டு மனுஷங்க. லட்சியவாதமோ கனவொ இல்லாத போலி முகங்க. அவங்கள்லாம் ஜஸ்ட் ஜெயிச்சவங்க டாக்டர். திருடியோ மோசடி பண்ணியோ பணமும் புகழும் அதிகாரமும் அடைஞ்சவங்க. அவங்கள முன்னால பாத்துட்டு ஒரு தலைமுறையே ஓடி வந்திட்டிருக்கு. அந்த பசங்க முன்னாடி இந்தா இப்டி ஒரு ஐடியலிஸத்துக்கும் இன்னும் நம்ம சமூகத்திலே எடமிருக்குன்னு சொல்லலாம்னு நினைச்சேன். இன்னும் இங்க காந்தி வாழறதுக்கு ஒரு காலடி மண்ணிருக்குன்னு சொல்லலாம்னு நினைச்சேன். ஒரு பத்துபேரு கவனிச்சாக்கூட போருமே டாக்டர்&#x27;.
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yaanai Doctor” is a novella that introduces us to Dr. V. Krishnamoorthy, who is affectionately known as Dr. K among the people residing in the vicinity. Dr. K is a dedicated professional working tirelessly for the well-being of both captive and wild elephants in Southern India. It’s a story of passion, compassion, and the extraordinary bond between Dr. K and these magnificent creatures.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I immersed myself in the novella, I discovered that while it may not have resonated deeply with me on a personal level, I found myself captivated by the skillful narration and the unique world it unveils.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the standout moments in the novella is when a herd of elephants makes a journey from Mudumalai to Top Slip, seeking medical aid for a calf in their midst. This poignant episode offers a glimpse into the complex relationship between humans and elephants, and the lengths to which individuals like Dr. K go to ensure their welfare.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is beautifully narrated from the perspective of a Forest Ranger who is determined to help Dr. K gain the recognition he truly deserves. The ranger’s efforts to have Dr. K acknowledged and honored by the public are at the heart of how the narrative unfolds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yaanai Doctor” takes readers on a remarkable journey through the world of elephant healing and conservation in Southern India. It is a story of devotion, hope, and the profound connection that can exist between humans and the animal kingdom. Jeyamohan’s storytelling prowess shines throughout the novella, offering a unique and heartwarming glimpse into a world that is both enchanting and vital.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my journey of exploring Jeyamohan’s works, “Yaanai Doctor” may not have struck a personal chord, but it certainly left a lasting impression. It is a tribute to the unsung heroes working to protect and care for our wildlife, reminding us of the importance of coexisting with the incredible creatures that share our planet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a penchant for tales of wildlife, compassion, and human-animal relationships, “Yaanai Doctor” is a must-read. It offers a fresh perspective on the wonders of nature and the extraordinary individuals who dedicate their lives to its preservation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Resurgence through Reading: My Journey with Haruki Murakami and &#x27;Killing Commendatore</title>
        <published>2023-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Manoprasanth MATHAVAN
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://kafkaa.xyz/blog/killing-commendatore/"/>
        <id>https://kafkaa.xyz/blog/killing-commendatore/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://kafkaa.xyz/blog/killing-commendatore/">&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;kc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Books of Murakami&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still vividly recall the exhilaration and sense of accomplishment that coursed through me when I completed my very first book. It was the work of Haruki Murakami that guided me on this literary journey. Without him, I doubt I would have developed the habit of reading. Everyone has an author who holds a special place in their heart; however, I’m not one to fawn over authors themselves, but rather the content they create. Yet, Murakami’s influence on instilling this reading habit in me makes me feel indebted to him.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“Reading was like an addiction; I read while I ate, on the train, in bed until late at night, in school, where I&#x27;d keep the book hidden so I could read during class. Before long I bought a small stereo and spent all my time in my room, listening to jazz records. But I had almost no desire to talk to anyone about the experience I gained through books and music. I felt happy just being me and no one else. In that sense I could be called a stack-up loner.”
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as abruptly as the reading habit had blossomed in my life, it mysteriously faded away, almost as if it had never existed. I ceased reading and lost all desire to pick up a book. Despite this, I still had a deep passion for purchasing books, naively hoping that my lost reading habit would return someday. Alas, it remained elusive. So there I was, stuck in a reading slump for over eight long months.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m hardly an expert capable of dispensing advice on how to rekindle the reading habit; ultimately, it’s a personal journey that one must navigate themselves. The solution is as simple as deciding to take a trip—if you want to go to Madurai, just go to Madurai. With that in mind, I turned to Murakami once again to help me break free from the reading rut. Unfortunately, I had already devoured most of his major works prior to the slump. It was during this time that I stumbled upon “Killing Commendatore,” a book that would reignite my passion for reading.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon discovering that the protagonist of the book was an artist, I didn’t hesitate for a moment before snatching it up. I was immediately captivated by the unfolding of the story, particularly the portrayal of the nameless artist’s mundane life. However, that’s where my admiration for the book ends. In the past, when I completed a piece of Murakami’s work, I was often left in a state of awe, but “Killing Commendatore” didn’t quite resonate with me. I wouldn’t say that I disliked it, but I found it challenging to fully grasp or connect with, at least from my perspective.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite my mixed feelings towards the book, I’m delighted to report that I’ve successfully emerged from my reading slump, thanks to Murakami’s magic. It’s the first time I’ve felt somewhat disenchanted with his work, but the important thing is that I’m back to enjoying books and reading once again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
