<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title> - experiments</title>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://kafkaa.xyz/tags/experiments/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://kafkaa.xyz/"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://kafkaa.xyz/tags/experiments/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>A month without media consumption</title>
        <published>2024-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Manoprasanth MATHAVAN
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://kafkaa.xyz/blog/no-media-consumption/"/>
        <id>https://kafkaa.xyz/blog/no-media-consumption/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://kafkaa.xyz/blog/no-media-consumption/">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I have had a notion to track my life. So, I started to track a few things since January ’24. Up until now my idea was just to track my actions and understand my habits better rather than pushing myself to maintain a streak on the actions. To give you an idea here is the representation of days on which I was reading a book.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;reading.png&quot;  alt=&quot;Days spent reading&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was probing for something on the Internet, I serendipitously ended up in this &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manuelmoreale.com&#x2F;without&quot;&gt;blog by Manu&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. To give you a brief, he gives up something for a month like caffine, videogames and then evaluate whether it was something he enjoyed giving up, and try to comprehend if it’s worth leaving it out of his life. It seemed fun and interesting so I decicded to give it a shot.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, for the month of June I decided to give up media cosumption, to narrow it down I decided to stop watching any form of moving images ranging from Youtube videos, Films, TV Series, Documentaries, or any form of Social Media.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though I didn’t fail miserably in this challenge. I managed to refrain from consuming media for the first ten days which is a small win to cherish for and after which I fell into the old patterns.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key observation during the initial phase was that my screen time drastically dropped from hours to minutes which I didn’t account for while planning. Also, I spent a lot of time reading. Another important thing was utter boredom, I was expecting to be hit by one eventually. Although going through it was kind of horrendous, it rekindled the good old days when I wasn’t connected to the Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
